Chicago, IL 60640 | 405.213.7722 I

mallory.hyneman@gmail.com

Summary

mhyneman.com

Developer with experience leading teams working on multiple objectives, while communicating effectively and maintaining project organization. Proficient with MERN full stack projects.

Skills

Web Accessibility - Web Hosting Responsive Web Design -TDD & BDD

PostgreSQL/MySQL - SQL & NoSQL

MongoDB - Node.js & Server-Side Programming

- Heroku

Git and Version Control - React Redux

Functional & OOP - Web Ethics & Data Security

Cross-Browser Testing and Debugging

Projects

MyFlix / Angular

AWS

11/2021

Mallory Hyneman

Built a movie app based on the existing REST API to view details and make a favorites list. View Site

Chat App / React Native

10/2021

Built an app that provides users with a chat interface and options to share images and their location. Used Firebase and Gifted Chat View Code

Meet App / React

9/2021

Created a serverless, progressive web app using TDD technique. It uses the Google Calendar API to fetch upcoming events. View Site

Experience

Mother B. Green Cleaning / Executive Assistant

2020 - Present, Chicago, IL

- Developed and stream-lined training material and process, creating more consistent and uniform outcomes across the cleaning teams.
- Utilized SquareSpace to modernize the company website, increasing consumer inquiry by 15%.
- Facilitated company growth through recruitment and onboarding of quality applicants, via job search platforms.
- Increased business revenue by 8%, through research and implementation of equipment rental services.

CPS - Al Raby High School / Science Teacher

2017 - 2019, Chicago, IL

- Created Women in STEM and Coding Clubs, introducing 20 students to coding and technical opportunities and expanding their future educational prospects.
- Active member of counsel that created and piloted Personalized Learning (PL) curriculums that were subsequently distributed school wide.
- Analyzed student data using formative/summative assessments to move students to mastery of state standards. 95% of students passed the state test.
- Petitioned for and awarded grant for development of new science course, including physics material and Van de Graff Generator for immersive and comprehensive classroom experience.

Languages

- HTML and CSS/SASS
- JavaScript & JQuery
- React
- React Native
- Angular

Education

CareerFoundry /Full-Stack **Development Certificate** 2021

Western Governors University / Master's in Science Education 2012 - 2014

Oklahoma State University / Bachelors in Biological

Sciences 2006 - 2011

Volunteer Work

National Runaway Safeline/ Liner - 1/18-Present

Utilize communication technology to offer a safe, non-judgemental space for youth to talk about the issues they face, such as abuse, neglect, and mental health.

Volunteer of the month

- Dec'18

Urban Rivers/Ranger -6/20-Present

Reporting on plant health and wildlife sightings; removing trash buildup, weeds and invasive species; measuring the installation's impact on the ecosystem

Lakeview Pantry- 7/20-Present

Assisting with preparation for Home Delivery and Pop-Up Pantry, packing produce and dairy, prepping dry/canned goods. Pack orders for Online Market

Ambassador

- July '21